

# **Hector Torres**

hitalz@icloud.com +1 (956) 279 3348 https://hitalz.github.io

#### **Profile**

As an experienced individual in the technology field, I can contribute towards the growth of organizations with my knowledge in systems administration, troubleshooting, testing, and programming. By being self-started and self-motivated I've been able to evaluate and integrate many systems, and easily adapt to company procedures.

### **Skills**

Systems: G Suite, Office365, Jamf, GoToAssist, osTicket, cPanel, AD, UniFi, WinBox/RouterOS, Joomla, Wordpress, Github. Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL, Swift, Bash, PowerShell. Databases: MySQL, SQL Server. Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tachyons. Operating/Virtual Systems: macOS, UNIX/Linux, Windows, Windows Server, VirtualBox, Parallels. Cloud services: Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform. Spoken Languages: Bilingual; English & Spanish full proficiency.

# **Experience**

# Almanza Villarreal Forwarding, Hidalgo, Texas

## Systems Administrator

November 2015 - Present

Perform all levels of hardware and software support to Windows and macOS machines to 130+ users, both locally and remotely. Maintain current assets inventory. Prepare and deploy new computer equipment.

- Provide support on printing issues, internet connectivity, Office 365, G Suite, and many other applications.
- Provide support to remote users via GoToAssist, phone, email and instant messaging.
- Document support inquiries via osTicket Support Ticket System.
- Conduct workshops and training sessions to staff on current applications.
- Elaborate documentation and how-to's on company and third-party applications.
- Mobile Device Management administration with Jamf and Apple Configurator.
- Maintain company website on Joomla and distribute email campaigns on Mailchimp.
- Deploy, maintain and configure network infrastructure including: Ubiquiti access points, routers and switches.
- Set-up, maintain, and configured osTicket Support Ticket System.
- Integrated a third-party digital clock in/out system that optimized and reduced payroll preparation time.
- Coordinated with third-party providers to move company applications to the cloud.
- Fulfilled contracts with different providers ranging from computer equipment to third-party applications.
- Integrated a third-party mobile warehouse system that improved load times and reduced shipment errors.
- Successfully implemented and migrated user data to G Suite.

## Rasmussen College, Bloomington, Minnesota

# Peer Tutor - Remote

September 2016 - November 2017

Conducted one-on-one tutoring sessions with students, facilitated the implementation of solutions to common software development issues by reviewing code and promoting problem-solving skills.

- Documented, and tracked student performance on Google Sheets, and Brainfuse.
- Followed up with students and communicated with fellow tutors via email, phone and instant messaging.
- Provided new hire training, training on learning services and participated in mock sessions with new tutors.
- Completed and held CRLA Level 1 Certified Tutor by accumulating over 100 hours of tutoring sessions.
- Maintained learning services resources with up to date information, and validating url's.
- Attended various webinars that promoted critical thinking, learning skills, and role modeling.
- Participated on monthly staff meetings, and promoted department goals.

# **Experience (cont.)**

# GTS International, Inc, Hidalgo, Texas

## **Operations Coordinator**

November 2011 - August 2013

Coordinated shipments to and from Mexico, managed delivery timelines, resolved customers inquires, created shipment orders.

- Maintained warehouse inventory up to date.
- Provided new hire training both on Traffic and Warehouse Department.
- Elaborated Shipper's Export Declaration throughout the Automated Export System.

#### Warehouse Specialist

September 2010 - November 2011

Performed different warehouse tasks that included fulfillment of shipment orders, loading and unloading of trucks, and monitored inventory.

- Certified Forklift Operator
- Mapped warehouse floor to optimize loading times.
- Followed OSHA safety guidelines and best practices.

## Casa SolSil, Cuauhtemoc, Mexico City

#### Office Assistant - Part time

September 2009 - November 2010

Assisted therapist in scheduling appointments and elaborating health/beauty products.

- Confirmed appointments and greeted patients.
- Received payments and performed bank deposits.
- Run errands with different providers.

## GTS International, Inc, Hidalgo, Texas

## Warehouse Assistant - Summer job

June 2007 - September 2007

Assisted warehouse staff on different tasks around the warehouse floor.

- Data entry of products into inventory system.
- Unloading and loading of products.
- Labeled, processed and fulfilled shipment orders.

#### **Education**

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**, GPA 3.16

August 2012 - November 2017

Rasmussen College, Bloomington, Minnesota

Studies focused on Full-Stack Web Development, Enterprise Architecture and iOS Development.

- Courses: Cloud Computing, Application Architecture, Business Intelligence, Database Management.
- WareInv. Web application written in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL that allows users to track warehouse inventory.
- RasTech. iOS application written in Swift that allows users to see the degrees and their courses thought at Rasmussen College.

## **Certifications**

Responsive Web Design by freeCodeCamp.

October 2018

IT Support Professional by Google.

September 2018

G Suite Administrator by Google Cloud.

July 2018

Level 1 Certified Tutor by the College Reading & Learning Association.

April 2017

# **Projects**

#### Current

- Regina Fernanda. Designer's website/portfolio written in HTML, CSS (+Bootstrap) and JavaScript (+jQuery).
- Almanza Villarreal. Company site made with Wordpress, customized according to company's needs.
- Ashtangamor. Business landing page written in HTML and CSS (+Bootstrap).

#### **Past**

• Regina Fernanda: Landing page written in HTML, and CSS (+Bootstrap).